SAMSUN NAHER

91 Kadamtala, Bashabo, Shabujbagh, Dhaka-1214

■ samsunnaherbithiac@gmail.com

******+8801685447536



Professional Summary

Accounting professional with 4.9 years of experience in accounts payable process. Responsible for all accounts payable duties and responsibilities at Crony Group & PDS Multinational Group. Specialized in handling accounting SAP, Tally & MS Excel.

Experience

Crony Group (Cronytex Sourcing Limited)

Department: Accounts & Finance

Position: Executive – Accounts (May 2021 to Till)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Bill Booking through software against approved PO.
- Vendor Payment through Cash/Bank payment entry in software.
- Asset Entry through software against approved PO.
- Month end expense wise Debit Note & Credit Note entry transfer to Overseas Office through software.
- Fund arrange from overseas office & timely submit C form to bank.
- Bank Reconciliation with the statement of bank and balance on ledger software.
- Recurring payable entries like-Rent Payable & Salary Payable.
- Implication of VAT TDS Payable to applicable bills & expenses.
- Month end expense wise VAT TDS challan submission to Govt. Treasury.
- 18B Quarter Report Submission for Liaison office.
- Preparing Quarterly Audit schedule for Internal Auditors.
- Half yearly Withholding Tax Return Submission.
- Courier Statement to analyze cost center wise expenses.
- Maintain proper documentation for all the accounting transaction month wise.
- Query handling for Internal & External Auditors, Vendors-regarding their outstanding balance.
- Preparing Aging report of Staff & Supplier vendor advances and take initiative to clear the balance.
- Preparing various report like Asset Record Statement, Travel Overseas, Travel Local & Employee Full & Final Statement assigned by the authority.

PDS Multinational Group (Styleberry Limited)

Department: Accounts & Finance

Position: Assistant Executive – Accounts (April 2018 to April 2021)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Bill Booking through SAP against approved PO.
- Vendor Payment through Cash/Bank payment entry in SAP.
- Bank Reconciliation with the statement of bank and balance on ledger (SAP).
- Recurring payable entries like-Rent Payable & Salary Payable.
- Implication of VAT TDS Payable to applicable bills & expenses.
- Month end expense wise VAT TDS challan submission to Govt. Treasury.
- 18B Quarter Report Submission for Liaison office.
- Preparing Quarterly Audit schedule for Internal Auditors.
- Half yearly Withholding Tax Return Submission.
- Courier Statement to analyze cost center wise expenses.
- Maintain proper documentation for all the accounting transaction month wise.
- Query handling for Internal & External Auditors, Vendors-regarding their outstanding balance.
- Preparing Aging report of Staff & Supplier vendor advances and take initiative to clear the balance.

PDS Multinational Group (Styleberry Limited)

Department: Accounts & Finance

Position: Junior Accountant (14th May 2017 to March 2018)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Bill Booking through SAP against approved PO.
- Vendor Payment through Cash/Bank payment entry in SAP.
- Implication of VAT TDS Payable to applicable bills & expenses.
- Month end expense wise VAT TDS challan submission to Govt. Treasury.
- Courier Statement to analyze cost center wise expenses.
- Maintain proper documentation for all the accounting transaction month wise.

PDS Multinational Group (Styleberry Limited)

Department: Accounts & Finance

Position: Trainee Accountant (13th November 2016 to 13th May 2017)

Duties/Responsibilities:

- Vendor Payment through Cash/Bank payment entry in SAP.
- Courier Statement to analyze cost center wise expenses.
- Maintain proper documentation for all the accounting transaction month wise.

On the Job Achievement:

Received Best Employee Award in 2018 for maintaining regular job responsibilities, effective communication and provide feedback to all the queries in a short span of time.

Areas of Expertise

- Accounts Payable
- ERP Accounting System- SAP, Tally
- Microsoft Excel

Educational Qualification:

Master of Business Studies from Eden Mohilla College (2010)

Major Accounting, 2nd Class.

Bachelor of Business Studies from Dhaka City College (2006 to 2009)

Major Accounting, 2nd Class

Higher Secondary Certificate from Siddheswari Girls' College (2005)

Major Concentration Business Studies, GPA: 3.70 out of 5

Secondary School Certificate from Kadamtala Purba Bashabo High School (2003)

Major Concentration Business Studies, GPA: 3.88 out of 5

Personal information

Father's Name: Md. Abul Bashar

Mother's Name: Subera Begum

Marital Status: Single

Religion Islam

Nationality: Bangladeshi (By birth)

Date of Birth: 15th October 1988

Reference

Ashok Yadava

Country FC – Accounts & Finance PDS Multinational Group House-490 Road-8, Baridhara DOHS

Cell: 01713006806

E-mail: ashok.yadav@osgbd.com

Navneet Paul

Country Manager Cronytex Sourcing Limited House-42, Nikhunja 1, Khilkhat, Dhaka.

Cell: 01713366628

E-mail: paul@cronytex.com

Muhommed Joinal Abedin

Sr. Manager - Accounts
PDS Multinational Group
House-490 Road-8, Baridhara DOHS

Cell: 01713490029

E-mail: joinal.abedin@osgbd.com

SAMSUN NAHER

Executive, Accounts & Finance Crony Group (Cronytex Sourcing Limited)